<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
  <title>Raymond Jacobsons Feed</title>
  <link>http://homepages.rpi.edu/~jacobr2/index.php</link>
  <description>A place to post</description>
<item>
<title>Really Amazing What Spring Can Do</title>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar, 2013</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Until today, the warmest weather we’ve had up here in Troy, NY has been in the low 40’s at best. Right now, it’s 55 degrees and unbelievably sunny. The entire campus of RPI has changed. It’s alive, bustling, and happy. A couple of my friends and I hiked up to the hill outside of the Sage Dining Hall to do work and take in the sun - something that I always looked for in a school when I went college visiting last spring. Just to give you a taste, we did work to this view:</p>
<img src="http://img32.imageshack.us/img32/9180/99901020090822373260919.jpg" width=”500”/>
<p>Until today, I wasn’t at my best. It wasn’t like I was depressed or anything, but I was stressed out and I guess just living/surviving day-by-day. And now, it’s totally different. It’s amazing how 15 degrees can change your mood entirely. I’ve been meaning to write a blog post for a while, but I was so busy with other stuff that blogging fell below other things on my list of priorities. Now, I feel rejuvenated, filled with energy, and really relaxed all at the same time, and with that I’ve felt the need to post something. So, as I’m writing this, sun’s shining through my window and Led Zeppelin’s “Over the Hills And Far Away” is playing outside. And it’s just so nice. I’ve had probably the most productive Saturday for months and I owe it to the sun. Thanks. I’ll post more often.</p>
<p>Oh, and also, I’ve implemented Disqus on my blog, so posts can be commented on now – not that there’s anything to really comment on with this post, but hey, if you’re here and inspired, how’s your spring? :)</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intro to Blogging/Not Exaggerating Enough</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb, 2013</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>So begins my first blog.</p>
<p>Over the past few years, as my thoughts have matured, I’ve begun to feel a need to put them down and forward my opinions, ideas, and ramblings. I never used to understand the point of “blogging,” but that’s sort of changed as I’ve gotten the feeling that if I were to have a place – a public place – to post things, I’d grow, learn, and share what’s important to me and hopefully somewhat important to people who might find themselves here. So, without further ado, I’ll begin my first post.</p>
<p>I’d like to talk a little bit about an essay written by Jared Diamond that was in January 28th's New York Times Science section titled “That Daily Shower Can Be a Killer.” You can find the article here: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/29/science/jared-diamonds-guide-to-reducing-lifes-risks.html">http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/29/science/jared-diamonds-guide-to-reducing-lifes-risks.html</a></p>
<p>In short, Mr. Diamond’s essay talks about how the inherent, small but frequent risks of living daily life are a lot more important than we make them out to be. He starts with the shower as an example. Mr. Diamond, 75, worries about falling (particularly in the shower) – a common cause of death for people his age. Obviously, the chances of falling in the shower are pretty slim (he gives a suggestion of a 1/1000th chance), but given the number of showers he plans to take by the time he’s 90, he claims he’ll have died five times. Broadening his statement, Mr. Diamond notes that during a trip to New Guinea he observed that with similarly frequent (shower type) risks, the New Guineans seemed to be more careful. He attributes that to societal factors.  In New Guinea, there are no doctors, police officers, or 911 dispatchers to save the day, so people are forced to “think clearly about dangers.” A fair point. So far.</p>
<img src="http://graphics8.nytimes.com/images/2013/01/29/science/29JPESSA/29JPESSA-popup.jpg"/>
<p>Mr. Diamond then draws a contrast between how New Guineans treat danger and how we, Americans, treat danger. That’s where I have issues with his piece.  He claims that, as a society, we “exaggerate the risks of events that are beyond our control, that cause many deaths at once or that kill in spectacular ways.” Crazy gunmen, terrorists, plane crashes, nuclear radiation, and genetically modified crops are some of such dangers “beyond our control” that we exaggerate.  Really? Is how much we care about what food we eat, whether there’s nuclear radiation, or whether we’re going to have another 9/11 exaggerated? Mr. Diamond feels that we should pay more attention to the smaller dangers instead.  “We obsess about the wrong things, and we fail to watch for real dangers,” he says. You’ve got to be kidding me.</p>
<p>Now, I understand where he’s coming from in saying we should pay more attention to smaller, frequent dangers. I think he’s right on. Paying more attention to lots of small dangers could potentially save lots of lives. Sure. But, I have a problem with the justification he uses for his argument. To say that we exaggerate risks of uncontrollable events is ridiculous. I don’t think we exaggerate them enough. Things are only uncontrollable until WE come up with a solution that makes them controllable.  I don’t think that there’s a limit or some ‘finite point’ where any further caring or trying to control gunmen, terrorists, radiation etc. is exaggerated. </p>
<p>Please. Be concerned more. Exaggerate more. The dangers and risks that caused Newtown, caused 9/11, and that make us think more about genetically modified goods (slightly more serious than Mr. Diamond’s shower) CAN be solved, and it’s our job, as a society, to obsess more until we can control them.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
